本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译创作
最新最快的HR-HDTV 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：兔子1m    spriteNT    allenlovestar    哈米波青
校对：emiliehe      监制：可乐嘻嘻      后期：哈利・鱼子酱
■
哈利・波特
与死亡圣器(下)
多比安眠于此
一个自由的小精灵
这里真漂亮
It's beautiful here.
是我姑妈的房子  我们小时候常来这里
It was our aunt's. We used to come here as kids.
凤凰社现在把它当做藏身之所
The Order uses it now as a safe house.
我们只能尽这点微薄之力了
What's left of us at least.
麻瓜认为这种东西能辟邪
Muggles think these things keep evil away.
但其实不是
But they're wrong.
我得跟妖精谈谈
I need to talk to the Goblin.
你还好吗
How are you?
还活着
Alive.
你可能不记得了
You probably don't remember that you...
你第一次去古灵阁时
That I showed you to your vault,
是我领你们去的金库吗
the first time you came to Gringotts.
哈利・波特  即使在妖精中间  你也很出名
Even amongst Goblins, you are famous Harry Potter.
你埋葬了那只小精灵
You buried the elf?
是的
Yes.
并把我带到这里
And brought me here.
你真是个
You are...
与众不同的巫师
...pretty unusual wizard.
你怎么得到那把宝剑的
How did you come by the sword?
一言难尽
It's complicated.
为什么贝拉特里克斯・莱斯特兰奇说
Why did Bellatrix Lestrange
这把剑应该在她的古灵阁金库里
think it should be in her vault at Gringotts?
一言难尽
It's complicated.
宝剑在危机时刻适时地出现在我们面前
The sword presented itself to us, in moment of need.
不是我们偷来的
We didn't steal it.
在莱斯特兰奇夫人的金库里
There is a sword in Madam lestrange's vault
有把一模一样的宝剑
identical to this one.
但那把是假的
But it is a fake.
是今年夏天放进去的
It was placed there this past summer.
她从未怀疑过它的真伪吗
And she never suspected it was a fake.
那个仿制品很逼真
The replica is very convincing.
只有妖精能鉴别出
Only a goblin would recognize
真正的格兰芬多宝剑
that this is the true Sword of Gryffindor.
还有谁知道这事
Who is the acquaintance?
一位霍格沃茨的教授
A Hogwarts Professor.
据我所知  他现在是霍格沃茨的校长
As I understand that he's now Headmaster.
斯内普
Snape.
他把假宝剑放在贝拉特里克斯的金库里
He put a fake sword in Bellatrix's vault.
为什么呢
Why?
在古灵阁的金库里
There are more than a few
存放着许多稀奇古怪的东西
curious things in the vaults at Gringotts.
莱斯特兰奇的金库也是如此吗
And in Madam Lestrange's vault as well?
也许吧
Perhaps.
我要潜入古灵阁
I need to get into Gringotts.
进入其中一个金库
Into one of the vaults.
这不可能
It is impossible.
单凭我  的确不行
Alone, yes.
但如果你帮我  就有可能
But with you, no.
-我凭什么帮你  -我有金子
- Why should I help you? - I have gold.
很多金子
Lots of it.
我对金子不感兴趣
I've no interest in gold.
那你想要什么
Then what?
那把剑
That.
这就是我开的价格
That is my price.
你认为贝拉特里克斯的金库里藏着魂器吗
Are you thinking there's a Horcrux in Bellatrix's vault?
她误以为我们进了金库时特别慌张
Well, she was terrified when she thought we had been in there.
不停地问你还拿了什么
She kept asking you, what else was taken?
我敢打赌  里面藏着一个魂器
I bet you anything, there's Horcrux in there.
装着他的另一片灵魂
Another piece of his soul.
只要我们找到并毁灭它
Let's find it, kill it,
就离杀死他的目标又进了一步
and we are one step closer to killing him.
找到它之后呢
And what happens when we find it?
你把宝剑给了拉环
How're we supposed to destroy it,
那我们用什么毁掉魂器
now you're giving the sword to Griphook?
我也在想办法
I'm still working on that part.
他很虚弱
He's weak.
是谁
Who?
奥利凡德先生
Mr. Ollivander.
我想问您几个问题
I need to ask you a few questions.
随意问  我的孩子  问吧
Anything, m'boy. Anything!
您能鉴定一下这根魔杖吗
Would you mind identifying this wand?
我们想知道它能不能用
We need to know if it's safe to use.
胡桃木制
Uhh... Walnut.
杖芯是龙的神经
Dragon Heartstring.
十二又四分之三英寸
12 and three quarter inches.
不易
Unyie...
不易弯曲
Unyielding.
这根魔杖是贝拉特里克斯・莱斯特兰奇的
This belonged to Bellatrix Lestrange.
小心使用它
Treat it carefully.
这根呢
And this?
山楂木制
Hawthorn.
杖芯是独角兽的毛
An unicorn hair.
十英寸
10 inches.
弹性尚可
Reasonably pliant.
这曾经是德拉科・马尔福的魔杖
This was the wand of Draco Malfoy.
曾经是
Was?
现在不是了吗
Is it not still?
如果被你夺取了  就可能已经易主
Well, perhaps not. If you won it from him.
我察觉到它效忠的对象已经改变
I sense its allegiance has changed.
您把魔杖说得好像它们有感情一样
You talk about wands, as if they have feelings...
好像它们可以思考
...can think!
魔杖选择巫师  波特先生
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter.
我们研究魔杖学问的人
That much has always been clear
都很清楚这一点
to those of us who've studied wandlore.
那您是否知道死亡圣器的事呢
And, what do you know about the Deathly Hallows?
据说有三个死亡圣器
It is rumored there are three.
老魔杖
The Elder Wand,
隐形衣
the Cloak of Invisibility,
用来躲避你的敌人
to hide you from your enemies,
还有复活石
and the Resurrection Stone,
能使你的心爱之人起死回生
to bring back loved ones from the dead.
谁拥有了这三样东西就能成为死神的主人
Together, they make one the Master of Death.
但很少人相信这种东西真的存在
But few, truly believe that such objects exist.
您呢
Do you?
您相信它们存在吗  先生
Do you believe they exist, sir?
我觉得不该去相信这种无稽之谈
I see no reason to put stock into an old wives' tale.
说谎
You're lying!
你明知其中一个确实存在
You know one exists.
并把它告诉了神秘人
You told him about it.
告诉了他关于老魔杖的事
You told him about the Elder Wand...
而且说出了去哪里找它
and where he could go looking for it.
他折磨逼问我
He tortured me.
而且
Besides...
我也只是讲了那些谣传
...I only conveyed rumors.
谁知道
There's...
谁知道他能不能找到它
There's no telling whether he will find it.
他已经找到了  先生
He has found it, sir.
您好好休息吧
We'll let you rest.
他在追杀你  波特先生
He's after you, Mr. Potter.
如果真如你所说
If it's true what you say,
他已拥有老魔杖
that he has the Elder Wand.
那么恐怕  你获胜的希望渺茫
I'm afraid, you really don't stand a chance.
那我就要在他找到我之前消灭他了
Well, I suppose I'll have to kill him before he finds me, then.
你确定这是她的头发吗
You're sure that's hers?
确定
Positive.
看起来怎么样
How do I look?
惨不忍睹
Hideous.
把它交给赫敏保管吧  拉环
You can give that to Hermione to hold. Alright, Griphook?
就靠你了  拉环
We're relying on you, Griphook.
如果我们能躲过守卫进入金库
If you get us past the guards into the vault...
宝剑就是你的了
The sword's yours.
莱斯特兰奇夫人
Madam Lestrange.
早上好
Good morning.
早上好  你竟然说早上好
Good morning? Good morning?
你是贝拉特里克斯・莱斯特兰奇  不是小女生
You're Bellatrix Lestrange, not some juvenile school girl!
别发这么大火
Hey! Easy!
如果她暴露了身份
If she gives us away,
我们就可以直接用那把剑自刎了
we must swear to use that sword to slit our own throats.
懂了吗
Understand?
他说得对
No, he's right.
我犯傻了
I speak stupid.
好了  走吧
Okay. Let's do it.
我要进入我的金库
I wish to enter my vault.
请出示身份证明
Identification?
我看没这个必要吧
I hardly think that would be necessary.
莱斯特兰奇夫人
Madam Lestrange.
我可没什么耐心等着
I don't like to be kept waiting.
我就知道
I know.
他们知道她是冒牌的
They know she's an impostor.
有人事先警告过他们
They'd be warned.
哈利
Harry.
该怎么办  哈利
What do we do, Harry?
莱斯特兰奇夫人  您能否出示您的魔杖
Madam Lestrange, would you mind presenting your wand?
这又是为何
And why should I do that?
这是古灵阁的规定
It's the bank's policy!
鉴于现在的时局  相信您能理解
I'm sure you understand, given current climate.
不  我当然不能理解
No! I most certainly do not understand!
恐怕我要坚持原则
I'm afraid, I must insist.
魂魄出窍
Imperio!
很好  莱斯特兰奇夫人
Very well, Madam Lestrange.
请您跟我来
If you will follow me?
那是什么  拉环
What is that, Griphook?
拉环
Griphook!
减缓下落
Aresto Momentum.
干得好  赫敏
Well done, Hermione.
糟了  你俩变回以前的样子了
Oh no, you two're like you again.
防贼瀑布  能洗掉所有的魔咒
The Thief's Downfall, washes away all enchantments.
有时候相当致命
Can be deadly.
还用你说
You don't say.
就是好奇问一句  还有别的方式出去吗
Just out of interest, is there any other way out of here?
没有
No.
你们几个在这里做什么
What the devil are all you doing down here?
小偷
Thieves!
你背弃了
You gave up the...
-魂魄出窍  -你
- Imperio. - You!
听起来不妙
That doesn't sound good.
我的天啊
Bloody hell!
乌克兰铁肚皮龙
That's an Ukrainian Ironbelly.
拿着
Here.
它经过训练  一听到这声音就会很痛苦
It's been trained to expect pain when it hears the noise.
太残忍了
That's barbaric!
荧光闪烁
Lumos.
天哪
Blimey!
魂器飞来
Accio Horcrux.
看来还得再试一次  不是吗
It seems you're gonna try that one again, aren't you?
咒语在这里面不管用
No kind of magic would work in here.
就在这里吗  哈利
It's in here, Harry?
你能感觉到它吗
Can you feel anything?
就在那儿  那上面
That's it! Up there!
他们加施了复制咒
They have added the Gemino curse.
你们碰到的任何东西都会复制
Everything you touch will multiply.
把剑给我
Give me the sword.
别动
Stop moving!
拿到了
Got it!
咱们说好的  拉环
We had a deal, Griphook!
宝剑换金杯
The cup for the sword!
我答应把你们带进来
I said I'll get you in,
可没答应把你们带出去
I didn't say anything about getting you out.
拉环
Griphook!
有贼
Thieves!
拉环
Griphook!
有贼
Thieves!
这可怎么办
Is that okay?
至少还有博格在
We've still got Bogrod.
太不幸了
That's unfortunate.
我们不能一直躲着  想到办法吗
We can't just stand here, you got any idea?
你是最聪明的那个
You are the brilliant one.
我有个想法  但是很疯狂
I've got something, but it's mad!
粉身碎骨
Reducto.
上来啊  你们俩
Well, come on, then!
力松劲泄
Relashio.
快跑啊
Keep moving!
现在怎么办
Now what?
粉身碎骨
Reducto.
抓紧
Hold on.
厉害  真厉害
That was brilliant! Absolutely brilliant!
我们在下降
We're dropping!
-我们跳下去吧  -什么时候
- I say we jump! - When?
现在
Now!
他知道了
He knows.
神秘人
You-Know-Who.
他知道我们闯进了古灵阁
He knows we broke into Gringotts.
他知道我们拿走了什么  也知道我们在找魂器
He knows what we took, and he knows we're hunting Horcruxes.
-你怎么知道的  -我看到了
- How is it you know? - I saw him.
你让他潜入意识了吗
You let him in?
哈利  你该封闭你的大脑
Harry, you can't do that!
赫敏  有时候我控制不住
Hermione, I can't always help it!
也许能控制  我也不知道
Well, maybe I can. I don't know!
先别管那个  到底发生了什么
Never mind! What happened?
他很愤怒
Well, he's angry,
也有些惊慌
and scared too.
他知道如果我们找到
He knows, if we find and destroy
并摧毁所有魂器  我们就能杀死他
all the Horcruxes, we'll be able to kill him.
我觉得他会不惜一切代价
I reckon he'll stop at nothing
阻止我们找到剩下的魂器
to make sure we don't find the rest.
还有
And there's more.
有一个魂器就在霍格沃茨
One of them is at Hogwarts.
什么
What?
你看到了吗
You saw it?
我看到了城堡
I saw the castle,
还有罗伊纳・拉文克劳
and Rowena Ravenclaw.
肯定跟她有关
It must have something to do with her.
我们必须马上回学校
We have to go there, now!
不能这样就去
Well, we can't do that!
我们要定个计划  好好想一想
We've got to plan, we've got to figure it out!
赫敏  我们哪次计划成功过
Hermione, when have any of our plans ever actually worked?
每次计划好  到达目的地  都会出各种状况
We plan, we get there, all hell breaks loose.
他说的对  但有个问题
He's right! One problem.
现在斯内普是校长
Snape's Headmaster now,
我们不能明目张胆地从正门进去
we can't just move from the front door!
我们先去霍格莫德  潜入蜂蜜公爵
Well, we'll go to Hogsmeade, to Honeydukes.
从地下室的暗道去学校
Take the secret passage in the cellar.
我觉得
It's...
我觉得神秘人有点不对劲
There's something wrong with him.
就好像  以前
It's like, you know, in the past,
我总能读懂他的思想
I've always been able to follow his thoughts.
但现在都是断断续续的画面
And now everything just feels disconnected.
也许是因为魂器
Maybe it's the Horcruxes.
也许他越来越虚弱了
Maybe he's growing weaker.
也许他快死了
Maybe he's dying!
不
No!
不  更像是他受了伤
No, it's...it's more like he's wounded.
他感到处境更加危险
If anything, he feels more dangerous.
那个男孩发现了我们的秘密  纳吉尼
导致我们身体日渐虚弱
必须倾尽全力找到他
而你  我的朋友  必须待在我身边
-这里  快点  -别放过任何一个角落
- Right here. Come on! - Search everywhere.
快点
Faster!
进来  波特
In here, Potter.
你有没看到他的脸
Did you look at him?
有那么一会儿我以为是...
For a second I thought that was...
我懂  以为是邓布利多
I know. Dumbledore!
哈利
Harry?
我能从镜子里看到你
I can see you in this.
你们这群傻瓜怎么想的  居然跑来这里
Bloody fools, what were you thinking, coming here?
你们知道这有多危险吗
Have you any idea how dangerous it is?
你是阿不福思  邓布利多的弟弟
You're Aberforth, Dumbledore's brother.
我在镜子里看到的就是你
It's you who I've been seeing in here.
多比是你派来的
You're the one who sent Dobby.
-你怎么丢下他了  -他死了
- Why've you left him? - He's dead.
我很难过  我喜欢那个小精灵
Sorry to hear it. I liked that elf.
那个是谁给你的
Who gave that to you?
那面镜子
The mirror?
大约一年前从蒙顿格斯・弗莱奇那买的
Mundungus Fletcher, 'bout a year ago.
顿格没权卖给你
Dung had no right selling that to you.
-它属于... -小天狼星
- It belongs to... - Sirius...
阿不思告诉我了
Albus told me.
他还说  你要是知道它在我手里
He also told me you'd likely be hacked off,
肯定会火冒三丈
if you ever found that I had it.
但你扪心自问
But, ask yourself:
如果我没有这镜子  你会身在何处
Where would you be if I didn't?
你有和别人联系吗
Do you have any others much?
凤凰社的人
From the Order?
凤凰社已经完了
The Order's finished.
神秘人赢了
You-Know-Who's won,
对此否认的人是自寻死路
anyone who says otherwise is killing themselves.
我们今晚得进入霍格沃茨
We need to get into Hogwarts, tonight.
邓布利多交给我们一项任务
Dumbledore gave us a job to do.
是吗
Did he now...
是美差吗  简单易行吗
Nice job? Easy?
我们一直在找魂器
We've been hunting Horcruxes.
我们认为最后一个在城堡里
And we think the last one's inside the castle.
我们需要你帮我们进入城堡
But we'll need your help getting in.
我哥哥这次无疑是让你们前去送死
Which job my brother has given you now, it's a suicide mission.
给自己条活路  孩子  回家去吧
Do yourself a favor, boy. Go home!
活久点
Live a little longer.
邓布利多相信我能办成这件事
Dumbledore trusted me to see this through.
你为什么相信他
What makes you think you can trust him?
你为什么相信
What makes you think you
我哥哥告诉你的一切
can believe anything my brother told you?
你和他相识这么久
And in all the time you knew him...
他有提到过我的名字吗
did he ever mention my name?
他有提到她的名字吗
Did he ever mentioned hers?
-他为什么要...-为了保密
- Why should he... - Keep secrets.
你说呢
You tell me?
-我信任他  -那是孩子的傻话
- I trusted him. - That's a boy's answer.
一个孩子听他的话去寻找魂器
A boy goes chasing Horcruxes on the
可他连一点头绪都没有给这个孩子
word of a man who wouldn't even tell him where to start.
你在撒谎
You're lying!
骗的不仅是我  这倒无关紧要
Not just on me, that doesn't matter.
你还欺骗自己
To yourself as well.
这是傻瓜行径
That's what a fool does.
你可不像是个傻瓜  哈利・波特
You don't strike me as a fool, Harry Potter!
我再问你一次  总得有个原因
So, I'll ask you again, there must be a reason.
你和你哥哥的恩怨与我无关
I'm not interested in what happened between you and your brother.
你放弃抵抗也不关我事
I don't care that you've given up.
我信任我所认识的邓布利多
I trusted the man I knew.
我们今晚得进入城堡
We need to get into the castle tonight.
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
你让她去哪里
Where've you sent her?
你会知道的
You'll see.
很快
Soon enough.
那是你妹妹  阿利安娜  对吗
That's your sister, Ariana. Isn't it?
很早就死了  对吧
She died very young, didn't she?
波特先生  在探求力量的道路上
My brother sacrificed many things, Mr. Potter.
我哥哥牺牲了许多
On his journey to find power.
包括阿利安娜
Including Ariana.
她爱他胜过一切
And she was devoted to him.
他也给了她一切
He gave her everything,
唯独少了时光
...but time.
谢谢你  邓布利多先生
Thank you, Mr. Dumbledore.
他救了我们两次
He did save our lives twice!
从镜子里注意着我们
Kept an eye on us on that mirror.
不像是已经放弃抵抗的样子
That doesn't seem like someone who's given up!
她回来了
She's coming back.
和她一起的是谁
Who's that with her?
纳威
Neville!
-你怎么看起来...-惨不忍睹  对吧
- How you look... - Like hell, I reckon.
这不算什么
This is nothing.
西莫还要惨
Seamus is worse.
阿不
Hey, Ab!
还有两个人要过来
We've got a couple more coming through.
我不记得活点地图上有这条路
Don't remember this on the Marauder's Map.
那是因为它是现在才通
That's because it never existed till now.
开学前他们就把七条秘道
The seven secret passages were sealed off,
全部封死了
before the start of the year.
这是唯一能进出的路了
This is the only way in or out, now.
学校里布满了食死徒和摄魂怪
The grounds are crawled with Death Eaters and Dementors.
斯内普的校长当得如何
How about Mr.Snape as Headmaster?
基本上看不到他人
Hardly ever seen.
是卡罗在看管我们
It's the Carrows who's watch out for.
卡罗
Carrows?
对  兄妹俩  管理纪律
Yeah. Brother and sister. Incharge of discipline.
卡罗兄妹最喜欢惩罚学生
They like punishment, the Carrows.
他们把你弄成那样的
They did that to you?
为什么
Why?
今天的黑魔法防术课是练习钻心咒
Today's Dark Arts lesson was practicing the Cruciatus curse.
在一年级生身上练习
On first years.
我不干
I refused.
霍格沃茨变了
Hogwarts has changed.
逗逗他们吧  好吗
Let's have a bit of fun, shall we?
大家听着
Hey, listen up you lot!
大惊喜
I've for you a surprise.
别又是阿不福思做的菜吧
No more Aberforth's cook gonna help.
能消化掉那玩意才是大惊喜
We'll be surprised if we can digest that.
-天啊  -哈利
- Oh my! - Harry!
告诉莱姆斯他们说哈利回来了
Get the word out to Remus and the others, that Harry is back.
好了  好了
Okay, okay!
可别抢先神秘人一步  把哈利烦死了
Let's not kill him before You-Know-Who does.
收到了吗  最新气象预报
Do you read? We've a new weather report.
闪电了  我重复一遍  闪电了
Lightning has struck. I repeat: Lightning has struck.
有什么好差事  哈利
What's the fun, Harry?
好吧
Okay.
我们得找出一样东西
There's something we need to find.
就藏在城堡里
Something hidden here, in the castle.
它也许能帮我们打败神秘人
And it may help us to defeat You-Know-Who.
-好的  是什么  -不知道
- Alright, what is it? - We don't know.
-藏在哪里  -也不知道
- Where is it? - We don't know that either.
我也知道线索不多
I realize there's not much to go on.
压根就没有线索
That's nothing to go on.
我觉得和拉文克劳有关
I think it has something to do with Ravenclaw.
东西很小  很容易藏
It'll be small, easily concealed.
有没有谁有点想法
Anyone, any ideas?
有一个  罗伊纳・拉文克劳失踪的冠冕
Well, there's Rowena Ravenclaw's lost diadem.
天哪  她又来了
Oh, bloody hell! Here we go!
拉文克劳失踪的冠冕
Lost diadem of Ravenclaw?
没人听说过吗
Hasn't anyone heard of this?
很有名的
It's quite famous.
没错  但它已经失踪了
Yes. But, Luna, it's lost.
失踪几百年了  如今活着的人都没见过它
For centuries. There's no person alive today who's seen it.
不好意思  冠冕到底是个什么玩意
Excuse me, can someone tell me what bloody diadem is?
是一种王冠
It's a sort of crown.
中间镶有一颗宝石的那种
You know, like a tiara.
哈利
Harry!
嗨
Hi, there.
时隔半年才见
Six months she doesn't see me
她居然把我当空气
and it's like I'm a frankie first-year.
我是她哥哥
I'm her brother!
她有一堆哥哥
She's got lots of them,
却只有一个哈利
but she's got only one Harry.
闭嘴  西莫
Shut up, Seamus!
怎么了  金妮
What is it, Ginny?
斯内普知道哈利在霍格莫德露过面了
Snape knows... he knows that Harry was spotted in Hogsmeade.
很多人肯定好奇
Many of you are surely wondering,
我为什么这个时候召集你们
why I have summoned you at this hour.
据我所知  今晚早些时候...
It's come to my attention, that earlier this evening...
有人在霍格莫德见过哈利・波特
Harry Potter was sighted in Hogsmeade.
现在
Now...
如若有人
should anyone...
无论是学生还是教工  试图帮助波特
student or staff attempt to aid Mr. Potter,
他们将会因此番行为
they will be punished in a manner
遭受严厉的惩罚
consistent with the severity of their transcription,
还有一点
further more...
如若有人获悉此行为
Any person found to have knowledge of these events...
而未通报的
who fails to come forward...
其罪同等
...will be treated as equally guilty.
另外...
Another...
如果有任何人
If anyone in here has any knowledge of
对波特今晚的行动有所了解
Mr. Potter's movements this evening.
我希望他能站出来
I invite them to step forward.
现在
Now!
看来  尽管你极尽防御之能事
It seems, despite your exhaustive defensive strategies,
这里还是有安全漏洞  校长先生
...you still have a bit of security problem, Headmaster.
而且还不小呢
I'm afraid it's quite extensive.
你怎么有脸站在他曾经的位置
How dare you stand where he stood?
告诉他们那晚发生了什么
Tell them how it happened that night?
告诉他们你是怎样看着他的眼睛
Tell them how you looked him in the eye...
杀死了那位完全信任你的长者
A man who trusted you, and killed him.
说呀
Tell them!
懦夫
Coward!!!
哈利
Harry.
波特
Potter?
我知道你们中有很多人想抵抗
I know that many of you will want to fight.
甚至有人觉得抵抗是明智的
Some of you may even think that to fight is wise.
但这是愚行
But this is folly.
把哈利・波特交出来
Give me Harry Potter.
把他交给我  谁也不会受伤害
Do this and none shall be harmed.
把他交给我  学校将完好无损
Give me Harry Potter, and I shall leave Hogwarts untouched.
把他交给我  你们将得到奖赏
Give me Harry Potter, and you will be rewarded.
给你们一个小时
You have one hour.
你们还在等什么  抓住他
What're you waiting for? Someone grab him!
学生下床了  学生下床了
Students out of bed! Students out of bed!
学生跑到走廊里啦
Students in the corridor!
他们本该如此
They're supposed to be out of bed,
你这胡言乱语的白痴
you blithering idiot!
对不起  女士
Sorry ma'am.
既然如此  费尔奇先生...
As it happens, Mr. Filch...
你来得正是时候
Your arrival is most opportune.
如果可以的话  我想请你
If you would, I would like you please,
把帕金森小姐及斯莱特林学院的带离礼堂
to lead miss Parkinson and the rest of Slytherin house, from the hall.
我该把他们带去哪  女士
Exactly where is it I'll be leading 'em to, ma'am?
地牢就可以
The dungeons would do.
波特  我想你回来是有理由的
I presume you have a reason for returning, Potter.
你需要什么
What is it you need?
时间  教授  尽量帮我争取时间
Time, Professor. As much as you can get me.
去吧
Do what you have to do.
我来守卫城堡
I'll secure the castle.
波特...
Potter...
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
我也是  教授
It's good to see you too, Professor.
守住城堡  纳威
Hold the fort, Neville.
快点走
Hurry up! Come on!
哈利
Harry!
赫敏和我一直在想
Hermione and I've been thinking,
找到魂器并没有用
it doesn't matter if we find a Horcrux.
什么意思
What do you mean?
除非我们有办法毁掉它
Unless we can destroy it.
所以  我们想...
So, we were thinking...
罗恩想  都是他的主意
Well, Ron was thinking, it was Ron's idea.
真是绝妙
It's completely brilliant.
你用蛇怪的牙毁了汤姆・里尔德的日记对吧
You destroyed Tom Riddle's diary with a Basilisk's fang, right?
我和赫敏想到  可以去密室再弄一颗
Well, me and Hermione did remind where we might find one.
好的
Okay.
好的  带上这个
Okay, but take this.
这样  你们回来的时候就能找到我
That way, you can find me when you get back.
你要做什么
Where're you going?
拉文克劳公共休息室  总得下手找吧
Ravenclaw common room, gotta start somewhere.
哈利
Harry!
我再确认一下  教授...
Let me get this straight, Professor...
您真的允许我们这样做吗
You're actually giving us permission to do this?
正确  隆巴顿
That is correct, Longbottom.
炸了它  嘭
To blow it up! Boom!
嘭
Boom!
帅呀
Wicked!
但怎么炸
But how on earth are we gonna do that?
你去跟斐尼甘先生商量吧
Why don't you confer with Mr. Finnigan?
我记得他有制造炸药的癖好
As I recall, he has a particular proclivity for pyro-technics.
我能搞定
I can bring it down.
这才对  快点去吧
That's the spirit! Away, you go.
你应该明白
You do realize, of course,
我们抵挡不了神秘人多久
we can't keep out You-Know-Who indefinitely.
但我们可以把他牵制住
That doesn't mean we can't delay him.
他的名字叫伏地魔
And his name is Voldemort.
菲利乌斯  你也该直呼其名
Filius, you might as well use it.
他不会因为你对他的称呼而杖下留人的
He's come to try to kill you, either way!
石墩出动
Piertotum Locomotor.
霍格沃茨正值危急时刻
Hogwarts is threatened.
守住边界  保卫我们
Man the boundaries! Protect us.
为学校尽你们的义务
Do your duty to our school.
我一直想用用那个咒语
I've always wanted to use that spell!
终极护防
Protego Maxima
固若金汤
Fianto Duri
抵挡敌方
Repello Inimigotum
终极护防
Protego Maxima
固若金汤
Fianto Duri
抵挡...
Repello...
终极护防
Protego Maxima
固若金汤
Fianto Duri
抵挡敌方
Repello Inimigotum
终极护防
Protego Maxima
哈利  等一下
Harry, wait!
我要和你谈谈
I need to talk to you!
卢娜我现在很忙
I'm a bit pre-occupied at the moment,Luna.
你根本不知道该去哪儿
You don't know anything where you're going.
你在浪费时间
You're wasting your time!
听着  我们以后再谈好吗
Look, we'll talk later, okay, Luna?
-哈利  -以后聊
- Harry? - Later.
哈利・波特你给我听好了
Harry Potter, you listen to me right now!
记得秋怎么说拉文克劳的冠冕的吗
Do you remember what Cho said about Rowena Ravenclaw's Diadem?
她说没有一个活人见过
There is not a person alive who's seen it.
这不明摆着吗
It's obvious, isn't it?
我们得去找个死人谈谈
We have to talk to someone who's dead.
很壮观  不是吗
It's very impressive, isn't it?
要见她的话  在这里能找到她
If you've to find her, you'll find her down there.
-你一起来吗  -不了
- Aren't you coming? - No.
我想你们单独谈比较好
I think it's best if you two talk alone.
她很腼腆
She's very shy.
你是格雷女士
You're the Grey Lady.
拉文克劳的幽灵
The ghost of Ravenclaw tower.
我不承认这个名讳
I do not answer to that name!
我很抱歉
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
你叫海莲娜  是吗
It's Helena, isn't it?
海莲娜・拉文克劳  罗伊纳的女儿
Helena Ravenclaw, Rowena's daughter.
你是卢娜的朋友吗
Are you a friend of Luna's?
是的
Yes.
她认为你也许能帮助我
And she thought you might be able to help me.
你在找我母亲的冠冕吗
You seek my mother's diadem?
是的
Yes.
是这样的
That's right.
卢娜人很好
Luna is kind.
和其他人不一样
Unlike so many of the others.
但是她说错了  我帮不了你
But she was wrong, I cannot help you!
请等一下
Wait, please!
我想要摧毁它
I want to destroy it!
他们就是不吸取教训
They never learn.
真可惜
Such a pity.
但是主人
But, My Lord...
我们不是该等等吗
Shouldn't we wait?
开战
Begin!
海莲娜  这也是你的心愿  不是吗
I thought you want to do it. Isn't it, Helena?
你想摧毁王冠吗
You want to destroy it?
许多年前  那个人也信誓旦旦说要摧毁它
Another swore to destroy it, many years ago.
一个有着奇怪名字的古怪男孩
A strange boy with a strange name.
汤姆・里德尔
Tom Riddle.
但他骗了我
But he lied.
他欺骗了很多人
He's lied to many people.
我知道他是谁  清楚他的所作所为
I know what he's done! I know who he is!
他用黑魔法玷污冠冕
He defiled it, with dark magic!
我能摧毁它
I can destroy it.
一劳永逸
Once and for all.
但得靠你告诉我  它藏在哪了
But only if you tell me where he hid it?
你知道地点的  对吗
You do know, where he hid it?
对不对  海莲娜
Don't you, Helena?
请告诉我
You just have to tell me.
拜托了
Please!
奇怪
Strange!
你和他有那么一点相似
You remind me of him a bit.
冠冕就在这城堡里
It's here, in the castle.
在一个隐藏万物之所
In the place where everything is hidden.
你若还需继续追问
If you have to ask...
便永远不会明白
....you will never know.
你若明白
If you know...
便只需开口索求
...you need only ask.
谢谢
Thank you!
告诉麦格教授
Tell Professor McGonagall.
我和莱姆斯负责城堡这侧的防御
Remus and I will handle this side of the castle.
是  先生
Yes, sir!
迪安  我又想了一下
Hey Dean, on second thoughts,
你去告诉她
tell Professor McGonagall
我们这边还需要一两个人
we might need one or two more wands this side.
一个人能否成功
It is the quality of one's
取决于他信念的坚定程度
convictions that determine his success...
而非随从的数量
...not the number of followers.
谁说的
Who said that?
我说的
Me.
弗雷德  你还好吗
You okay, Freddie?
很好
Yeah.
我也是
Me too.
开门
[蛇语]
哈利常说梦话
Harry talks in his sleep.
你知道吗
Do you know this?
当然不知道
No, of course, not!
来呀  有本事你就来呀
Yeah? You and whose army?
你来吧
You do it.
我不行
I can't.
你行的
Yes, you can!
纳威
Neville!
计划成功了
That went well.
快进去  这边走  找掩护
Get inside! This way! Take cover! Take cover
昏昏倒地
Stupefy
金妮  纳威  你们没事吧
Ginny, Neville! You alright?
好极了
Never better!
我觉得自己都可以喷火了
I feel like I can spit fire!
你见到卢娜了吗
Have you seen Luna up here?
卢娜
Luna?
我为她痴狂
I'm mad for her.
是时候向她表白了
I think it's about time I told her
我们可能都活不过今晚了
since we'll probably both be dead by dawn.
我懂
I know.
我的神  这地图上怎么找到他啊
Bloody hell! We'll never find him on this.
他在这儿
Here he is!
-在这儿  -好眼力
- Just now... - Brilliant!
他消失了
He just vanished.
刚才还看到的
I just now I saw it.
也许他去了有求必应屋
Maybe he's gone to the Room of Requirement.
那地方在地图上不显示的
It doesn't show up on the map, does it?
你去年说过
You said that last year.
对  我是说过
That's right, I....I did.
我们走
Let's go.
真厉害
Brilliant!
快来
Come on!
看啊
Well, well...
什么风把你吹来了  波特
What brings you here, Potter?
这话应该我问你
I could ask you the same.
你手头有我的东西
You have something of mine.
我想要回来
I'd like it back.
你手上这根魔杖有什么不好
What's wrong with the one you have?
它是我妈的
It's my mother's.
很强大  但是
It's powerful, but it's...
和我的不一样
...not the same.
不太能理解我
Doesn't quite understand me.
你懂我的意思吧
You know what I mean?
你为什么不告诉她
Why didn't you tell her?
贝拉特里克斯
Bellatrix?
你知道那就是我
You knew it was me.
却缄口不语
You didn't say anything.
动手吧  德拉科
Come on, Draco!
别犯傻
Don't be a prat.
动手吧
Do it!
别紧张
Easy!
除你武器
Expelliarmus.
阿瓦达索命
Avada Kedavra.
昏昏倒地
Stupefy.
敢打我女朋友  你们这帮混蛋
This is my girlfriend, you bloody gits!
拿到了
Got it!
高尔把这鬼地方给点着了
Goyle's set the bloody place on fire!
快  这边走
Come on! This way!
不能扔下他们
We can't leave them!
他开玩笑的吧
He's joking, right?
要是被他们拖死  我就杀了你  哈利
If we die for them, Harry, I'm gonna kill you!
哈利
Harry!
主人
My Lord?
阿达瓦索命
Avada Kedavra!
来吧  纳吉尼  我要保证你的安全
Come Nagini, I need to keep you safe.
是那条蛇
It's the snake.
它是最后一个
And she's the last one.
最后的魂器
It's the last Horcrux.
哈利  窥探他的内心
Look inside him, Harry.
寻觅他的行踪
Find out where he is,
他在哪儿  蛇就在哪儿
if you find him, we can find the snake.
我们就能了结这一切了
And we can end this!
主人
My Lord...
是不是稍许
Might it be less...
谨慎起见还是暂停此次攻势
I should not be more prudent to call off this attack.
只为了找那男孩
Simply seek the boy.
就劳您亲自出马
Yourself.
不用我去找那男孩
I do not need to seek the boy...
不出今夜
before the night is out,
波特就会上门来找我  你明白吗
he will come to me! Do you understand?
看着我
Look at me!
卢修斯  你怎么还有脸活着
How can you live with yourself, Lucius?
我不知道
I don't know.
去找西弗勒斯
Go and find Severus.
带他来见我
Bring him to me.
我知道他在哪儿
I know where he is.
冲啊
Come on!
不
No!
主人  就在这过去的几小时内
You have performed extra-ordinary
您已经用这根魔杖
magic with this wand, My Lord,
施展了力量非凡的魔法
in the last few hours alone.
不对
No!
非凡的是我  但魔杖在排斥我
No! I am extra-ordinary. But the wand resists me.
没有比它更强大的魔杖了
There is no wand more powerful.
奥利凡德说过
Ollivander himself has said it.
若那男孩今晚来了
Tonight, when the boy comes.
这魔杖不会让你失望  我很肯定
It will not fail you, I am sure of it.
它只听从于你  别无他人
It answers to you, and you only.
是吗
Does it?
主人
My Lord?
这魔杖真的听从于我吗
The wand, does it truly answer to me?
西弗勒斯  你是明白人
You're a clever man, Severus.
你应该知道
Surely you must know...
-魔杖真正的所属  -属于您
- ...where does its true loyalty lie? - With you.
毋庸置疑  主人
Of course, My Lord.
老魔杖没能顺应我
The Elder Wand cannot serve me properly,
因为我不是它真正的主人
because I am not its true master.
老魔杖属于那个杀死他前任主人的巫师
The Elder Wand belongs to the wizard who killed its last owner.
是你杀了邓布利多
You killed Dumbledore, Severus.
只要你活着  这魔杖就不会真正归属于我
While you live, the Elder Wand cannot truly be mine.
西弗勒斯  你是一个好仆人  忠心耿耿
You've been a good and faithful servant, Severus.
但只有我能永生不死
But only I can live forever.
主人
My Lord...
纳吉尼  杀了他
Nagini, kill!
快拿去
Take it.
把它收集起来  求你了
Take it up, please!
有容器吗  快  瓶子什么的
Give me something! Quickly, a flask. Anything!
放进冥想盆里
Take them to the Pensieve.
看着我
Look at me.
你的眼睛和你母亲的真像
You really have your mother's eyes.
纵然你们奋勇抗战
You've fought valiantly,
也是枉然
but in vain.
这非我所愿
I do not wish this.
巫师的血  每流一滴都是极大的浪费
Every drop of magical blood spilled is a terrible waste.
因此  我下令撤军
I, therefore command my forces to retreat.
在此期间
In their absence,
体面地安葬死者
dispose your dead with dignity.
哈利・波特
Harry Potter,
现在我直接和你对话
I now speak directly to you.
今晚
On this night,
你听任你的朋友为你赴死
you have allowed your friends to die for you,
而不是挺身出来面对我
rather than face me yourself.
如此行径无耻至极
There is no greater dishonor.
与我在禁林里相见
Join me in the Forbidden Forrest...
直面你的命运吧
...and confront your fate.
若你不来
If you do not do this,
我会赶尽杀绝所有
I shall kill every last man,
胆敢窝藏你的人
woman and child
不论男女老少
who tries to conceal you from me.
大家都去哪儿了
Where's everybody?
哈利
Harry?
算了  别太难过了  人死不能复生
Oh, come on! Don't be sad on it, she's passed.
她走了
There, she's gone.
怪胎  过来
Freak! Come here!
我去告诉妈妈  你是个怪胎
I'm gonna tell mommy! You're freak!
莉莉你是个怪胎
You're freak, Lily!
快过来
Come here!
她妒忌你  她很平庸  你却不同寻常
She's jealous. She's ordinary and you're special.
西弗勒斯  这么说太过分了
That's mean, Severus.
格兰芬多
Gryffindor!
-你好  我是詹姆斯  -你好  我是莉莉
- Hi, I'm James. - Hi, I'm Lily.
和你父亲一个德性
Just like your father.
别说我父亲的坏话
Don't say a word against my father!
仆人与主人会再次相逢
Servants and masters shall be reunited once more!
西弗勒斯
Severus.
不  别杀我
No, don't kill me!
那预言没提到什么女人
The prophecy did not refer to a woman.
是关于一个七月末出生的男孩
It spoke about a boy born at the end of the July.
是的  但是他认为是她的儿子
Yes, but he thinks it's her son!
他想要追杀他们
He intends to hunt them down and to kill them.
把他们藏起来  我请求你
Hide him... hide them all. I beg you!
西弗勒斯你怎样回报我呢
What would you give me in exchange, Severus?
任你差遣
Anything.
哈利
Harry...
哈利我们爱你
Harry, you were so loved.
太爱你了  妈妈爱你
So loved! Harry, mama loves you.
爸爸爱你
Dadda loves you.
哈利  你要好好的
Harry, be safe.
要坚强
Be strong.
阿瓦达索命
Avada Kedavra!
你说你会保证她的安全
You said you would keep her safe.
莉莉和詹姆斯
Lily and James...
错信了他人  西弗勒斯
..put their faith in the wrong person, Severus.
不像你
Rather like you.
那孩子活下来了
The boy survives.
他不需要保护  黑魔王不复存在了
He doesn't need protection, the Dark Lord has gone.
黑魔王会回来的
The Dark Lord will return.
到那时候  那男孩会有生命危险
And when he does, the boy will be in terrible danger!
他眼睛和他母亲的很像
He has her eyes.
如果你真的爱她
If you truly loved her...
别告诉任何人
No one, can know.
我绝不会美化你  西弗勒斯
I shall never reveal the best of you, Severus.
你保证
Your word?
你能冒性命之危  时刻保护那孩子吗
Can you risk your life every day to protect the boy?
这孩子资质平庸
He possesses no measurable talent,
他的傲慢甚至和他父亲不相上下
his arrogance rivals even that of his father
似乎还挺享受自己的名声
and he seems to relish in his fame.
不许说我父亲的坏话
Don't say a word against my father!
詹姆斯・波特  懒惰  傲慢
James Potter, lazy, arrogant.
-我父亲很了不起  -你父亲是头蠢猪
- My father was a great man! - Your father was a swine!
喝了它  这会把魔咒
Drink it up, it will contain
暂时遏制在一只手里
the curse to your hand, for the time being.
-它会扩散  阿不思  -我还能活多久
- It will spread, Albus. - How long?
大概一年
Maybe a year.
不要逃避  西弗勒斯
Don't ignore me, Severus.
我们都了解  伏地魔
We both know Lord Voldemort
下令让马尔福家的那个男孩杀死我
has ordered the Malfoy boy to murder me.
但如果他失败了  我想黑魔王会让你接替
But should he fail, I should presume the Dark Lord will turn to you.
必须由你来杀死我  西弗勒斯
You must be the one to kill me, Severus.
这是唯一的办法
It is the only way.
只有这样  黑魔王才会完全信任你
Only then, will the Dark Lord trust you completely.
会有那么一天
It will come a time,
你必须告诉哈利・波特一些事情
when Harry Potter, must be told something.
但你必须等到伏地魔最虚弱的时候
But you must wait, until Voldemort is at his most vulnerable.
必须告诉他什么
Must be told what?
伏地魔去戈德里克山谷杀哈利的那晚
On the night, Lord Voldemort went to Godric's Hollow to kill Harry,
莉莉・波特用生命挡在他们之间
and Lily Potter cast herself between them.
咒语反弹了
The curse rebounded.
那时  伏地魔灵魂的一部分
When that happens, a part of Voldemort's soul
附着在周围唯一的活物上
latched itself onto the only living thing it could find.
就是哈利他自己
Harry himself.
所以哈利有了与蛇对话的能力
There's a reason Harry can speak with snakes.
还能窥探伏地魔的思想
There's a reason he can look into Lord Voldemort's mind.
伏地魔灵魂的一部分依附在他体内
A part of Voldemort lives inside him.
所以  待到时机成熟  那男孩必须赴死吗
So, when the time comes, the boy must die?
是的...是的  他必须赴死
Yes... yes. He must die.
你让他活着  只是让他到时候去赴死
You've kept him alive, so he can die at the proper moment?
就像养一头猪  最后宰了
You've been raising him like a pig for slaughter.
不要告诉我  你开始关心起那个男孩了
Don't tell me now, that you've grown to care for the boy.
呼神护卫
Expecto Patronum.
莉莉的守护神
Lily!
时隔多年依旧如此?
After all this time?
一直如此
Always.
所以  待到时机成熟
So, when the time comes,
那男孩必须赴死
the boy must die?
是的
Yes.
他必须赴死  而且必须由伏地魔亲自动手
He must die. And Voldemort himself must do it.
必须如此
That is essential.
-你去哪儿了  -我还以为你去了禁林
- Where've you been? - I thought you went to the forest.
我现在要去那儿
I'm going there now.
你疯了吗  不行...
Are you mad? No...
你不能把自己交出去
You can't give yourself up to him.
怎么了  哈利
What is it, Harry?
你知道什么了
What is it you know?
我能听到它们  是有原因的
There's a reason I can hear them.
魂器
The Horcruxes.
我想我早就知道原因了
I think I've known for a while.
我想你也是
And I think you have, too.
-我和你一起去  -不  把蛇杀死
- I'll go with you. - No, kill the snake.
把蛇杀死  就只剩下伏地魔自己了
Kill the snake, and then it's just him!
我在结束时打开
我准备好赴死了
I'm ready to die.
复活石
Resurrection Stone.
你真勇敢  宝贝
You've been so brave, sweetheart.
你们怎么都来了
Why are you here? All of you.
我们从未离开过
We never left.
疼吗
Does... Does it hurt?
死亡
Dying?
比进入梦乡还要快
Quicker than falling asleep.
你就要成功了  儿子
You're nearly there, son.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我从未想过让你们为我死去
I never wanted any of you to die for me.
还有  莱姆斯  你的儿子
And, Remus, your son?
其他人会告诉他  他父母是为何而死的
Others will tell him what his mother and father died for.
总有一天  他会明白的
One day, he'll understand.
你们会陪着我吗
You'll stay with me?
直到最后
Until the end.
他看不见你们吗
And he won't be able to see you?
看不见
No.
我们在你心里
We're here, you see.
待在我身边
Stay close to me.
永远都在
Always.
没有他的影子  主人
No sign of him, My Lord.
我原以为他会来
I thought he would come.
哈利  不
Harry, no!
-你到这儿来干什么  -闭嘴
- What're yeh doin' here? - Quiet!
哈利・波特...
Harry Potter...
大难不死的男孩...
The Boy Who Lived...
来受死了
come to die.
阿瓦达索命
Avada Kedavra.
你帮不了
You can't help.
哈利  你这个出色的孩子
Harry, you wonderful boy.
勇敢的男子汉
You brave, brave man!
一起走走吧
Let us walk.
教授  那是什么
Professor, what is that?
是我们都无能为力的一种东西
Something beyond either of our help.
伏地魔死去的一部分灵魂
A part of Voldemort sent here to die.
我们究竟是在哪儿呢
And exactly where are we?
我正打算问你呢
I was going to ask you that.
你说我们是在哪儿
Where would you say that we are?
看起来像是国王十字车站
Well, it looks like King's Cross station.
只是要干净许多
Only cleaner,
而且没有火车
and without all the trains.
国王十字车站  真的吗
King's Cross, is that right?
就像人们说的  这的确是你的地盘
This is, as they say, "your" party.
我想你现在已经知道你和伏地魔
I expect you now realize that you and Voldemort
不仅是因为命运安排而联系在一起
have been connected by something other than fate.
更因为多年前那晚  在戈德里克山谷发生的事
Since that night in Godric's Hollow, all those years ago.
看来是真的了  先生
So it's true then, sir.
伏地魔灵魂的一部分附在我身上  是吗
A part of him lives within me, doesn't it?
附过
Did.
就在刚才
It's been just destroyed
它被伏地魔自己给摧毁了
many moments ago by none other than Voldemort himself.
你是他无意间制造的魂器  哈利
You, were the Horcrux he never meant to make, Harry.
-我必须回去  是吗  -这由你决定
- I have to go back, haven't I? - Oh, that's up to you.
-我可以选择吗  -是的
- I've a choice? - Oh, yes!
你说我们在国王十字车站
We're in King's Cross, you say.
只要你想好了
I think if you so decide,
就可以登上一列火车
you'll be able to board a train.
它会把我带到哪儿呢
And where would it take me?
前方
On.
伏地魔有老魔杖
Voldemort has the Elder Wand.
没错
True.
蛇还活着?
And the snake's still alive?
是的
Yes.
我拿什么杀他
And I've nothing to kill it with?
在霍格沃茨  那些请求帮助的人
Help will always be given at Hogwarts,
总会如愿  哈利
Harry. To those who ask for it.
我一直为自己出口成章的能力而自豪
I've always pride of myself on my ability to turn a phrase.
不谦虚的说  我认为语言
Words are, in my not so humble opinion,
是最取之不尽的魔力源泉
are most inexhaustible source of magic.
能治愈伤害  抚平伤痕
Capable of inflicting injury and remedies.
但这次  我要收回原来的话
But I would in this case, amend my original statement to this:
在霍格沃茨  那些值得帮助的人
Help, will always be given at Hogwarts,
总能如愿
to those who deserve it.
不要怜悯死者  哈利
Do not pity the dead, Harry.
怜悯生者
Pity the living.
尤其  要怜悯那些心中无爱的人
And above all, all those who live without love.
教授  我妈妈的守护神
Professor, my mother's Patronus,
是一只牝鹿  是吗
was a doe, wasn't it?
和斯内普教授的一样
As the same as Professor Snape's.
您不觉得这很奇妙吗
It's curious, don't you think?
实际上  在我看来  这一点也不奇妙
Actually, if I think about it, it doesn't seem curious at all!
我要先走了  哈利
I'll be going now, Harry.
教授
Professor?
这一切是真实的吗
Is this all real?
或者只是发生在我脑中的事
Or is it just happening inside my head?
当然是发生在你脑子里的事  哈利
Of course it's happening inside your head, Harry.
但那为什么不能是真实的呢
Why should that mean, that it's not real?
教授
Professor?
我该怎么做
What should I do?
教授
Professor!
主人  主人...
My Lord, My Lord...
您受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
我不需要帮助
I don't need your help.
那个男孩...他死了吗
The boy... Is he dead?
他还活着吗
Is he alive?
德拉科还活着吗
Draco, is he alive?
他死了
Dead.
那是谁
Who is that?
海格抱着的是谁
Hagrid's carrying?
纳威  那是谁
Neville, who is it?
哈利・波特...死了
Harry Potter... is dead!
不
No!
安静
Silence!
蠢女孩
Stupid girl!
哈利・波特...死了
Harry Potter... is dead!
从今天起  你们要效忠于我
From this day forth... you'll put your faith in me.
哈利・波特死了
Harry Potter is dead!
是宣誓效忠的时候了
And now it's the time to declare yourself.
要么站出来加入我们
Come forward and join us,
要么受死
or die!
德拉科
Draco!
Draco.
德拉科
过来
Come.
干的好  德拉科
Well done, Draco.
干的好
Well done!
我还以为能站出来个像样的
Well, I must say I'd hoped for better.
你是谁  年轻人
And who might you be, young man?
纳威・隆巴顿
Neville Longbottom.
纳威  我们定能给你腾出个地方
Well, Neville, I'm sure we can find a place for you in our rank.
我有话要说
I'd like to say something.
好吧  纳威
Well, Neville, I'm sure we'd
不妨说来听听
all be fascinated to hear what you have to say.
-哈利死去了也没关系  -回来  纳威
- Doesn't matter that Harry is gone. - Stand down, Neville!
每天都有人死去
People die everyday!
朋友  家人
Friends, family.
是的
Yeah.
我们今晚失去了哈利
We lost Harry tonight.
但他仍然与我们同在
He's still with us.
在我们心里
In here.
就像弗雷德  莱姆斯  唐克斯一样...
So as Fred, Remus, Tonks...
所有逝者
All of them.
他们没有白白死去
They didn't die in vain.
但你们会
But you will.
因为你们错了
Because you're wrong!
哈利的心还在为我们而跳动
Harry's heart did beat for us.
为我们所有的人
For all of us!
还没结束呢
It's not over!
霹雳爆炸
Confringo.
快跑
Come on!
所有人都待在城堡里
All remain into the castle.
我们必须杀掉那条蛇
We have to kill the snake.
纳威
Neville!
不许碰我女儿  你这母狗
Not my daughter, you bitch!
你是对的
Hey, you were right,
当你告诉斯内普教授老魔杖不听你指挥时
when you told Professor Snape that wand was failing you.
它永远不会听命于你
It will always fail.
我杀了斯内普
I killed Snape!
但如果老魔杖从未听命于斯内普呢
But what if the wand never belonged to Snape?
如果它一直效忠于其他人呢
What if its allegiance is always to someone else?
来吧  汤姆
Oh, come on, Tom...
我们怎么开始  就怎么结束吧
Let's finish this the way we started.
一起
Together!
去死吧
Die!
哈利
Harry!
为什么它不听命于伏地魔
Why didn't it work for him?
老魔杖
The Elder Wand?
它听命于其他人
It answered to somebody else.
他杀了斯内普后
When he killed Snape,
就以为老魔杖真正属于他了
he thought the wand would become his.
但事实是...
But the thing is...
老魔杖从未属于过斯内普
The wand never belonged to Snape.
它属于德拉科  那晚
It was Draco, who disarmed
他在天文塔除去了邓布利多手中的魔杖
Dumbledore that night in the Astronomy tower.
从那时开始  魔杖就效忠于他了
From that moment on and the wand answered him.
直到那晚我夺去了德拉科的魔杖
Until, the other night when I disarmed Draco.
在马尔福庄园
At Malfoy Manor.
所以  那就意味着...
So, that means...
它属于我了
It's mine!
-我们应该用它来做些什么  -我们
- What should we do with it? - We?
只是说说而已  这可是老魔杖
Just saying, that's the Elder Wand.
世界上最强大的魔杖
The most powerful wand in the world.
有了它  哈利可以战无不胜了
With that, he'd be invincible.
十九年后
一起吧
Together.
-包背好了?  -好了
- Bag? - Yeah.
套头衫呢
Jumper?
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
他们来了
Here they come.
爸爸
Dad?
如果我被分进了斯莱特林怎么办
What if I am put in Slytherin?
阿不思・西弗勒斯・波特
Albus Severus Potter.
你是以霍格沃茨两位校长的名字命名的
You were named after two Headmasters of Hogwarts.
其中一位就是斯莱特林的
One of them was a Slytherin.
他是我见过的最勇敢的人
And he was the bravest man I've ever known.
可是如果...
But just say if I am...
那斯莱特林学院就会多出一位
Then Slytherin house will have gained
出色的年轻巫师
a wonderful young wizard.
但是听着  如果你真的很在意的话
But listen, if it really means that much to you,
你可以选择格兰芬多
you can choose Gryffindor.
分院帽会考虑你的选择
The Sorting Hat takes your choice into account.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Really.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Ready? - Ready.
人人影视电影翻译小组
谨以此片献给所有观众
Farewell!  Harry Potter!